<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="Windstille">
  
  <section title="Open Tasks">
    <ul>
      <li>
        create a 3D model of the hero with <a
          href="http://www.blender3d.com">Blender</a> <strong>[done, but needs
          lots of polishing]</strong>
      </li>

      <li>
        create run, jump and shoot animations for the 3dD model <strong>[done,
          but needs lots of polishing]</strong>
      </li>
      
      <li>
        generate sprites from this model <strong>[done]</strong>
      </li>
      
      <li>
        find a name for the hero, create a small story <strong>[framework
          mostly done]</strong>
      </li>
      
      <li>
        create a first real playable release, with at least a single
        level, something with enemies and a bit of hero-environment
        interaction
      </li>

      <li>
        create a level editor
      </li>

      <li>
        more bells and whistles, little birds, other animals, grass
        moving in the wind, waterdrops, clouds in the background
        and/or foreground (dust).
      </li>
    </ul>
  </section>

  <section title="Game Design Documentation">
    <subsection title="Actions">
      <subsubsection title="Jump">
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Shoot">
        <p>
          Should the hero be able to shoot in different directions or
          should be stick to a MegaMan like shooting?
        </p>
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Surround">
        <p>
          Basically a turrican style surround shooting. Not sure how
          the thing will shoot (ice-freeze, flamethrower, normal). I kind
          of like it to behavice like a flamethrower to remove slime or
          other poison liquids on the ceiling or ground, which are immune
          against and unreachable with other weapons.
        </p>

        <img src="images/surround.jpg" />
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Sit">
        <img src="images/sit.jpg" />
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Run/Walk">
        <p>
          We might have seperate walk and run actions (basically like
          in Super Mario), don't know if that will work out well, so
          we might end up with only a run action.
        </p>
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Hang">
        <p>
          <img src="images/posing4.jpg" />
        </p>
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Climb">
        <p>
          <img src="images/posing2.jpg" align="right"/>
          <img src="images/posing3.jpg" align="right" />
          
          The Hero should be able to climb both wall and roof ladders.
        </p>
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Swim/Underwater">
        <p>
          Swimming should basically be a 'endless' jump. You might
          also be able to simply walk underwater. [FIXME: This doesn't
          fit dogether with the otherwise planed realistic movement]
        </p>
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsection title="Weapons">
        <p>
          Will we need different weapon stages like Turrican or static
          ones? (Weaponstage &lt;-&gt; Hero's energie!?)
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Jetpack">
        <p>
          The game will have a jetpack, I am currently not sure if we
          have it as a item which you can use all the time or just in some
          special events/levels.
        </p>

        <img src="images/jetpack.png" />
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Light/Torch">
        <img src="images/flashlight.png" />
        <img src="images/flashlight2.png" />
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Machinegun">
        <img src="images/machinegun.png" />
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Plasmagun">
        <img src="images/plasmagun.png" />
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Lasergun">
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Flamegun">
        <img src="images/flamegun.png" />
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Rocketlauncher">
        <p>
          Rocketlauncher can hold missiles
        </p>
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Missile">
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Homing Missile">
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Smart Bomb - Shockwave">
        <p>
          Turrican 2 style, but maybe circular, which
          basically means that the bomb will not erase anything on the
          screen, but only these enemies which are reachable from the
          heros position.
        </p>

        <img src="images/shockwave.jpg" />
      </subsubsection>

      <subsection title="Bonus Items">
      </subsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Power Up">
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Machinegun ammunition">
      </subsubsection>

      <subsubsection title="Plasmagun ammunition">
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsubsection title="Laser energie">
      </subsubsection>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Enemies">
      <subsubsection title="Respawning"> 
        <p>
          Big enemies, final bosses and similar things should not
          respawn. Small standard enemies should respawn at specific
          events (level/section change).
        </p>
      </subsubsection>
      
      <subsection title="Levels">
        <p>
          The game will not be sperated into normal levels, instead it
          will consist of 'sections', where one can more or less move
          freely around. Translating between section will be done via
          special events (like the water-thing in another world) or
          via doors (where one has to find the keys before passing
          them). Moving forward and backward should basically
          possible, but there might be points-of-no-return. Some kind
          of guidance system should always show you where to go, so
          that one doesn't lost himself in a level.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection title="Different types of assault suits">
        <subsubsection title="Standard">
          <p></p>
        </subsubsection>

        <subsubsection title="Ice">
          <p>might protect against ice water and give better grip on ice</p>
        </subsubsection>

        <subsubsection title="Fire/Lava">
          <p>
            protect better against lava and hot regions
          </p>
        </subsubsection>

        <subsection title="Level File Format">
          <p>
            The level file format will be at its basic level tile
            based, support for multiple overlapping tiles would be
            nice, the tile size will be 128x128. In addition the map
            might support brushes, meaning you can insert (animated)
            surface objects at arbitrary positions, not sure how this
            will influence the collision map.
          </p>
        </subsection>

        <subsubsection title="Collision Map">
          <p>
            needs to be modifiable, should use a tilesize of 8x8
            pixels (the smallest possible world object). How to we
            integrade non-flat ground? Might need more than one pixel
            type. Water, Lava must also be handled by this map.
          </p>
        </subsubsection>
        
        <subsubsection title="Collision detection">
          <p>
            Collision detection should be pixel-precision.
          </p>
        </subsubsection>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection title="Backgrounds">
        <p>
          We will support multiple paralax scrolling layers of
          backgrounds. The implementation will/should be similar to
          Pingus.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection title="Cutscenes">
        <p>Not sure what we need here</p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection title="In game Events">
        <p>Not sure what we need here.</p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection title="Dialogs">
        <p>
          We should provide some kind of primitive dialog support,
          nothing complicated, simple yes/no dialogs might do it.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection title="Controller - Gamepad Mappings">
        <p>
          The game will be designed for use with a 8 button pad (4 action
          button, 1 pause button, 1 select, 2 shoulder button)
        </p>

        <ul>
          <li>jump (action button)</li>
          <li>shoot (action button)</li>
          <li>smartbomb [a selectable secondary weapon?] (action button)</li>
          <li>weapon change (action button) / tertiary button</li>
          <li>pause</li>
          <li>map, weapon assign (select)</li>
          <li>surround - shoulder button</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
          A flewible controller api should be provided for remapping
          the buttons to specific gamepads.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection title="Items">
        <p>
          We might include items which can trigger specific
          switches, cutscenes or story events. They might also be
          used to open doors, detonate walls or similar things. Item
          selection should be similar to weapon select (a rotating
          pie-menu)
        </p>

        <img src="images/weaponitemselect.jpg" />
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection title="Layers">
        <p>
          The game engine should be build up-on different abstraction
          layers, each of these should only depend on the previous layer
          and should be mainly independet of the game itself, so allowing
          to reuse it for other games.</p>

        <ul>
          <li>1. Layer -> ClanLib</li>
          <li>2.1 Layer -> Tilemap based worlds</li>
          <li>2.2 Layer -> Particle System</li>
          <li>3. Layer -> WorldObj's, Framework for enemies</li>
          <li>4. Layer -> The Game itself, enemies special effects</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>

      <subsection title="Screen Items/layer">
        <ul>
          <li>player-energiebar</li>
          <li>weapon-energiebar</li>
          <li>current weapon icon</li>
          <li>armor/player icon</li>
          <li>map/radar</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection title="Releases">
        <p>
          I am not sure how releases will be handled. Release 1.0.0
          should be a fully playable and complete version, other versions
          should also be playable, but maybe not all. Development releases/
          technical previews should be seperated from playable demos and
          should provide a special interface which lets you select level,
          intros, etc. The init/intro screen should show that the current
          version is not playable.
        </p>

        <p>It might take three years or longer until a fully playable
          version is ready, demos might be ready a few weeks after I started
          coding.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section title="Tiles">
    <p>
      Tiles in Windstille are 128x128 pixel large, there collision
      handling however happens at 16x16 pixels. This means that a tile
      is seperated into 8x8 subtiles.
    </p>
    
    <p align="center">
      <img src="images/8x8.jpg" />
      <img src="images/8x8-1.jpg" />
    </p>

    <p>
      Which of these subtiles is collidable and which isn't is setup
      in the <tt>data/tiles.scm</tt> file. So to create a tile one
      needs to paint a 128x128 large tile and make sure that any edges
      of it align with the 16x16 subtiles so that collision handling
      can go smoothly. A little overlap is ok and necessary to make it
      look good, but the player shouldn't be allowed to 'walk in
      stone', so overlap shouldn't get to huge. The yellow areas above
      mark transition-subtiles, aka. tiles that are only half
      collidable and present a 45 degree angle.
    </p>
  </section>
</page>