<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="Windstille">
  
  <section title="Introduction">
    
    <img src="images/character.png" align="right" alt="" style="position: relative; left: 0px;"/>

    <p>
      In Windstille the player will be placed in a foreign alien world
      and has to find its way back into safety. Special focus will be
      on getting the foreign world and the players character itself
      believable. Exploration will be more needed than plain shoot
      action, even so the players-character will be equipped with a
      multifunctional war-suit, so he will be far from defenseless.
      The game will have slow placed explore and seak sequences as
      well as more rough section that will feature fast shoot and jump
      action. The game world should be presented in a consistent
      state, enemies once destroyed should not respawn automatically.
      The player is free to go forward and backward in the world as
      long as the level design allows it.
    </p>

    <subsection title="Visuals">
      <p>
        The game will be presented in a classic 2d jump'n run
        perspective, while multiple layers of tile-maps, zooms,
        parallax scrolling and fluent animations should give the world
        a plastic and realistic feeling.
      </p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Enemies">
      <p>
        The main opponents in the first few levels will be animals,
        like insects or spiders, from the foreign world. Doding them
        instead of fighting them might often be a valuabl choice, even
        so the player should have a good amount of freedom about how
        he solves the problem he is facing.
      </p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Scripting">
      <p>
        To allow a wide varity of puzzles and story events inside the
        game, it will have to rely on a scripting engine, namly <a
          href="http://www.gnu.org/software/guile/">Guile</a>. Game
        content should be influencable quite a lot by scripting so
        that level designers and script writers have the freedom
        needed to create a compelling game.
      </p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection title="Relations to other games">
      <p>
        If somebody now thinks this sounds similar to Another World,
        Flashback, Turrican, Metroid or Prince of Persia he is quite
        right, all these games have been a big source of inspiration,
        but simply cloning them is not the point of this project.
      </p>
    </subsection>

    <div style="text-align: right;">
    <!-- Begin Nedstat Basic code -->
    <!-- Title: Windstille -->
    <!-- URL: http://www.nongnu.org/windstille/ -->
    <script language="JavaScript" type="text/javascript" src="http://m1.nedstatbasic.net/basic.js">
    </script>
    <script language="JavaScript" type="text/javascript" >
      <!--
      nedstatbasic("ACX4aQxswZiE89THkqOnM7mV5Y/g", 0);
      // -->
    </script>
    <noscript>
      <a target="_blank" href="http://v1.nedstatbasic.net/stats?ACX4aQxswZiE89THkqOnM7mV5Y/g"><img
          src="http://m1.nedstatbasic.net/n?id=ACX4aQxswZiE89THkqOnM7mV5Y/g"
          border="0" width="18" height="18" 
          alt="Nedstat Basic - Free web site statistics" /></a>
    </noscript>
    <!-- End Nedstat Basic code -->
    </div>
  </section>

</page>
