<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="Windstille">
  
  <section title="News">
    <news>
      <item date="1. Mar 2009">
        New <a href="wiki/">Windstille Wiki</a> got launched.
      </item>

      <item date="15. Feb 2009">
        Some Windstille development is going on again, check out the 
        <a href="http://grumbel.blogspot.com/search/label/Windstille">Blog</a>. Windstille
        Wiki is going to be restructured, so its not updated anymore
        at the moment.
      </item>

      <item date="20. Oct 2007">
        Windows build of the 0.3.0 release is available
      </item>

      <item date="13. Jun 2007">
        <a href="download.html">Windstille 0.3.0</a> is out, featuring:
        <ul>
          <li>near complete rewrite of the engine</li>
          <li>3D sprites</li>
          <li>light effects</li>
          <li>particle system</li>
          <li>model viewer</li>
          <li>menu system</li>
          <li>scripting</li>
        </ul>
      </item>

      <item date="23. Jun 2005">
        On 25. June 2005, 18:00 GMT we will have a developer IRC
        meeting in <tt>irc.freenode.net</tt>, channel
        <tt>#windstille</tt>. Everybody interesting in joining is
        welcome.
      </item>

      <item date="20. Jun 2005">
        There is currently a lot of stuff happening to Windstille,
        with a little luck we might have something actually playable
        ready in a few month. All development specific information is
        now collected in the <a
                                href="http://windstille.berlios.de/wiki/index.php/Main_Page">Windstille
          Development Wiki</a>.
      </item>

      <item date="3. Jun 2005">
        Some more pictures of our still nameless <a href="artworks.html#hero">hero {f}</a>.
      </item>

      <item date="5. Nov 2004">
        We now have a <a
                         href="http://windstille.berlios.de/phpBB2">forum</a> where you
        can post suggestion, comments and whatever you want. <em>Forum
          is currently no longer online.</em>
      </item>

      <item date="3. Nov 2004">
        The <a href="screenshots.html">screenshot section</a> has a
        new <a href="images/screenshot9.jpg">screenshot</a> showing
        the lightmap support in Windstille, there are also a few new
        pics in the <a href="artworks.html#hero">artwork section</a>.
      </item>

      <item date="24. Oct 2004">
        A video of a fire effect created by the particle system that
        will be used in Windstille is now available in the <a
                                                              href="screenshots.html#effects">effects subsection</a>
      </item>

      <item date="16. Oct 2004">
        Some more screenshots of hour hero and some more sketches of
        scenery are available in the <a href="artworks.html">artwork
          section</a> are available.
      </item>

      <item date="06. Oct 2004">
        Some new lighting effects are now in the <a
                                                    href="screenshots.html#effects">artwork section</a>.
      </item>

      <item date="04. Oct 2004">
        Not much news in the last few months, but don't worry, its not
        dead yet, just developing rather slowly and jumpy. The <a
                                                                  href="artworks.html">artwork section</a> contains some new
        pieces (<a href="artworks.html#hero">here</a> and <a
                                                             href="screenshots.html#effects">here</a>) of graphics which might
        be worth a look. You want to see the Windstille artwork in its
        purest or rawest form, you can now find it in the <a
                                                             href="http://undone.clanlib.org/~grumbel/show.cgi?search=windstille">Game
          Media Repository</a>.
      </item>

      <item date="08. Feb 2004">
        A updated <a href="download.html">Win32 release</a> is
        available, fixes the small bugs mentioned below.
      </item>

      <item date="08. Feb 2004">
        Thanks to <a href="mailto:rkon@gmx.de">Robert Konrad</a> we
        now have a Win32 build of the <a href="download.html">0.2.0
          Windstille release</a>, known bugs for that release include
        the lack of the exit-trigger, so once you have reached the
        exit, you have to press Escape.
      </item>

      <item date="02. Feb 2004">
        Added another, a bit more detailed, <a
                                               href="images/artwork10.jpg">artwork of the Windstille
          hero</a>. Win32 release will hopefully follow real soon. Hint:
        If anybody wants to help maintaining the Win32 builds and thus
        lead to faster release cycles and less workload on myself,
        tools for doing that (MinGW, ClanLib, Voribs, etc.) are all
        Free Software and freely downloadable from the net..
      </item>

      <item date="14. Jan 2004">
        Windstille 0.2.0 is out, at the moment just the GNU/Linux is
        available, Windows version will follow soon. There is also a
        video of it available <a href="http://pingus.seul.org/~grumbel/tmp/windstille-400x300-xvid.avi">here</a>.
      </item>

      <item date="29. Aug 2003">
        A first Win32 release got crossy-compiled, not public available,
	but it should ensure that following Windows ports should be doable
	in relativly small amounts of time.
      </item>
      
      <item date="13. Aug 2003">
        <a href="download.html">Windstille 0.1.0</a> is out, both the
        full source and a static binary for GNU/Linux are provided,
        this is the first useable Windstille version. Its currently
        not more then a simple techdemo so don't expect anything
        playable.
      </item>

      <item date="09. Aug 2003">
        Added a few <a href="screenshots.html#pseudoscreen">pseudo
          screenshots</a>, aka artworks that use in-game graphics and a
        few other things to emulate special effects.
      </item>

      <item date="07. Aug 2003">
        Added a few <a href="screenshots.html#posingtest">posing
          tests</a>, rewrote the <a href="index.html">introduction</a>.
      </item>

      <item date="04. Aug 2003">
        Added another artwork, some minor webpage cleanups.
      </item>      

      <item date="28. Dec 2002">
        Added little <a href="images/background1.jpg">desktop background</a>.
      </item>

      <item date="1. Sep 2002">
        Ported Windstille to ClanLib-0.7-CVS (compiles, but doesn't work).
      </item>
    </news>
  </section>

</page>
